But poisoning someone who comes to visit you in the hospital.
Tapi, meracuni seseorang yang datang menjengukmu di rumah sakit.
To be honest, maybe this hospital is cursed.
Sejujurnya, mungkin rumah sakit ini dikutuk.
There was rumor going round that an announcer named Rena Mizunashi
Ada rumor yang menyebar bahwa seorang penyiar bernama Rena Mizunashi
was hospitalized here.
dirawat di sini.
Then wounded people avalanched in causing chaos.
Lalu orang yang terluka berbondong-bondong ke sini menimbulkan kekacauan.
I also heard that there was a bombing commotion here too.
Aku juga dengar bahwa ada keributan pengeboman juga di sini.
Officer Takagi!
Petugas Takagi!
Don't you have to return to MPD already?
Bukankah kau harus kembali ke Kepolisian?
Oh, no!
Oh, tidak!
Then, you don't know of a man called Rikumichi Kusuda, do you?
Maka, kau tidak tahu seorang pria bernama Rikumichi Kusuda, bukan?
Rikumichi Kusuda?
Rikumichi Kusuda?
Now that you mentioned it,
Sekarang kau menyebutkannya,
a few days before the bombing incident that I just mentioned,
beberapa hari sebelum insiden pengeboman yang baru kusebutkan,
a damaged vehicle was found near here,
sebuah kendaran hancur di temukan di dekat sini,
and the owner of that vehicle was a man called Rikumichi Kusuda!
dan pemilik kendaraan itu adalah seorang pria bernama Rikumichi Kusuda!
It was a case full of mysteries.
Itu sebuah kasus penuh dengan misteri.
Inside that damaged vehicle a great amount of splattered blood
Di dalam kendaraan yang hancur itu
was found all over the vehicle.
percikan darah ditemukan di seluruh kendaraan itu.
Some of the blood stains were less than a millimeter across.
Semprotan darah dari penembakan bahkan tidak satu milimeter pun.
-According to forensics... -Blood stains less than a millimeter across
-Menurut forensik... -Semprotan darah dari penembakan kecepatan tinggi
from high speed shooting.
bahkan tidak satu milimeter pun.
A pistol?
Sebuah pistol?
Let's use the years we walked together as a springboard.
Didorong maju oleh tahun yang dihabiskan bersama.
And move forward full speed without slowing down.
Maju dengan kecepatan penuh tanpa memperlambat kecepatan.
A strange case occurs at Haido Park.
Sebuah kasus misterius di Taman Haido.
A bright red secret starts to spill.
Sebuah rahasia merah mulai terkuak.
He sees through the one and only truth.
Dia melihat satu-satunya kebenaran.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
Memiliki penampilan seorang anak kecil dengan kepintaran orang dewasa.
His name is Detective Conan!
Namanya adalah Detektif Conan.
"Haido Elementary School"
"SD Haido"
Hello.
Halo?
Oh, Jodie! What's up?
Oh, Jodie. Ada apa?
Oh, was it today that we were supposed to go drinking?
Apa kita bilang kita akan pergi minum hari ini?
Have you already gotten used to being an elementary school teacher?
Apa kau sudah terbiasa dengan pekerjaan mengajar sekolah dasarmu?
Yes. I'm really popular being their beautiful teacher
Ya. Semua orang menyukai guru cantik mereka
who returned from abroad.
yang kembali dari luar negeri
"Natsuko Shibuya (28)" -Is what I'd like to say.
"Natsuko Shibuya (28)" -adalah hal yang ingin kukatakan.
But it's really a hard work.
Tapi banyak pekerjaan.
I'm supposed to meet some parents today after this too.
Aku seharusnya menemui beberapa orang tua setelah ini.
I see.
Begitu.
I guess we can't go out drinking tonight then.
Aku rasa kita tak bisa pergi minum malam ini.
No. I'm sorry.
Yah, maaf.
By the way, why are you still in Japan?
Bagaimanapun, kenapa kau masih di Jepang?
Your undercover investigation is over, right?
Penyelidikan penyamaranmu sudah berakhir, bukan?
Hey, you're the one who invited me out for drinks.
Hei, kau mengundang aku untuk minum.
I've got my reasons too.
Aku punya alasanku sendiri.
Secrets on the job, right?
Rahasia resmi, bukan?
Right.
Itu benar.
I'll call you again then.
Aku akan meneleponmu nanti.
Your friend?
Apa itu temanmu?
Yes. When she was studying abroad in the US,
Ya. Dia terlibat dalam sebuah kasus
she got involved in a case.
selagi belajar di Amerika.
I saved her back then.
Dan aku menyelamatkan dia.
And that's how I got to know her.
Kami saling mengenal sejak itu.
I see.
Benarkah?
She also taught me Japanese
Dia juga mengajariku bahasa Jepang
and helped me go undercover as an English teacher.
dan membantuku menyamar sebagai guru bahasa Inggris.
I guess you could say she's my best teacher friend.
Kurasa kau boleh bilang kami adalah teman guru.
I see.
Begitu.
And? Who are you waiting for here?
Jadi siapa yang sedang kita tunggu?
Natsuko Shibuya, age 28.
Natsuko Shibuya, 28 tahun.
An elementary school teacher.
Guru sekolah dasar.
Who's that?
Siapa dia?
My client
Klienku
as well as the one who can lead me to the last piece I'm looking for.
dan seseorang yang mungkin membantuku
A woman who could probably help me complete the puzzle.
mengisi potongan terakhir teka-teki yang sedang kucari.
So, what is this piece that you're referring to?
Dan potongan apakah itu?
That sound just now sounded like someone fell down the stairs.
Apa seseorang jatuh dari tangga?
Hey, come on. Let's go!
Ayo kita pergi.
I don't want to attract attention is a place like this.
Kita tak bisa menarik perhatian.
She's...
Wanita ini...
Yes.
Ya.
I guess the puzzle'll be completed soon.
Kurasa aku akan segera melengkapi teka-tekinya.
"The Scarlet Prologue"
"Prolog Scarlet"
"Teitan Elementary School"
"SD Teitan"
Hey, Conan!
Hei, Conan!
Let's play soccer on the way home.
Ayo kita bermain sepakbola dalam perjalanan pulang!
What?
Hah?
He's gone!
Dia tidak ada di sini!
He rushed out as soon as the bell rang.
Dia bergegas keluar ketika belnya berdering.
Over there.
Di sana!
I wonder if someone came to pick him up by car?
Apa seseorang menjemputnya?
I'm sure it's Pops from the detective agency!
Itu pasti pria tua dari agensi detektif.
No, it's not.
Tidak.
That car is an expensive foreign car.
Itu adalah sebuah mobil impor mahal.
I don't think Pops would rent a car like that.
Pria tua itu takkan menyewa mobil semacam itu.
I see.
Oh, benar.
Oh, then maybe it's Ms. Jodie's car.
Mungkinkah itu mobil Nn. Jodie?
It's only natural for a foreigner to be driving a foreign car.
Takkan aneh bagi orang asing untuk mengendarai sebuah mobil impor.
Come on.
Ayolah.
Let's leave that deduction freak alone
Lupakan tentang penggila misteri itu.
and head home!
Ayo kita pulang.
Dr. Agasa said he'd buy a delicious cake for us.
Dokter Agasa bilang dia akan membeli kue.
It seems Edogawa doesn't want any,
Sepertinya Edogawa tidak menginginkannya.
so let's eat it up ourselves!
Mari kita menikmatinya tanpa dia.
-Yes! -Let's do that!
-Ayo! -Ayo kita pergi!
Right.
Ya.
That's definitely the car of the FBI that I've seen before.
Itu mobil FBI yang kulihat sebelumnya.
Your priority purpose is to retrieve the transmitter and wiretap!
Prioritasmu adalah mengambil kembali pemancar dan penyadapnya.
Don't hesitate because of unneeded curiosity and righteousness,
Jika kau ragu karena penasaran atau rasa kebenaran,
because then everything is lost!
kau akan kehilangan segalanya!
Yeah. I know.
Ya, aku tahu.
But, he hasn't cautioned me of anything,
Tapi karena dia tidak memberitahuku apapun,
which means something's come up.
sesuatu pasti terjadi.
Something out of my sight.
Sesuatu terjadi di luar penglihatanku.
Ai!
Ai!
What're you doing?
Apa yang sedang kau lakukan?
I'm hungry so let's hurry back!
Aku lapar! Cepat!
Yep, I'm coming.
Aku akan ke sana.
What kind of cake is it?
Kue apa itu?
Let's eat it together, Haibara.
Mari kita memakannya bersama.
Yes.
Ya.
Rikumichi Kusuda?
Rikumichi Kusuda?
You mean the spy from the Organization that snuck into the hospital
Mata-mata organisasi yang menyusup rumah sakit
where Rena Mizunashi was staying.
dimana Rena Mizunashi berada.
If I remember correctly,
Seingatku,
he fled after his identity was exposed.
dia lari ketika penyamarannya terbongkar.
After Shu caught and cornered him,
Begitu Shu menyudutkan dia,
he shot himself in the head with a gun.
dia menembak kepalanya sendiri.
Right?
Benar?
-Yeah. -What about that?
-Ya. -Bagaimana dengannya?
Please tell the people at the FBI to not leak this information.
Beritahu FBI untuk merahasiakannya.
One of the guys of the Organization, Bourbon,
Pria organisasi, Borbon,
Tohru Amuro is sniffing around, you see!
Tohru Amuro sedang melakukan sebuah penyelidikan.
Sure thing!
Tentu saja!
What?
Apa?
Did you ask me to come pick you up just to tell me that?
Kau membuatku menjemputmu hanya untuk memberitahu itu?
Yes because it's easy to wiretap a cell phone.
Ya. Ponsel mudah disadap.
And I have something else I have to tell you too.
Di samping itu, ada hal lain.
Maybe...
Mungkin...
Maybe that guy called Amuro is...
Mungkin Amuro adalah...
Three! Two! One!
Tiga! Dua! Satu!
Zero!
Zero!
Oh, sorry.
Ah, maaf.
I'm going to pull over and answer it.
Aku akan menepi agar aku bisa menjawab ini.
What? Natsuko's in critical condition?
Apa? Natsuko terluka parah?
She fell off the stairs in front of Haido Park?
Dia jatuh dari tangga di Taman Haido?
What hospital is she at?
Rumah sakit mana?
I'll head over right away.
Aku akan menuju ke sana.
Oh, no, I'd like you to come to the crime site.
Sebenarnya, kami ingin kau datang ke tempat kejadian.
Crime site?
Tempat kejadian?
Yes. I'm at the place where she fell off the stairs now.
Ya. Kami berada di tempat di mana dia jatuh.
We found from the call history on her cell phone
Sejarah panggilan pada telepon miliknya yang kami temukan di taman
that she talked to you last night before eight pm.
menunjukkan dia bicara denganmu sebelum pukul delapan malam semalam.
That's right.
Itu benar.
I called her just around that time.
Aku menelepon dia saat itu.
Hold it!
Tunggu.
You mean she didn't fall accidentally?
Apa dia tidak jatuh karena kecelakaan?
No.
Tidak.
According to the person who reported it from a nearby phone booth,
Menurut orang yang melaporkannya dari telepon umum di dekat sini,
it seems she'd been pushed down by someone.
seseorang mendorongnya.
Hello? Jodie?
Halo? Jodie?
I'll be right over!
Bagaimanapun, aku akan ke sana.
The place is the stairs in front of Haido Park, correct?
Aku akan menemuimu di tangga di Taman Haido.
Jodie.
Jodie.
Camel? What are you doing here?
Camel! Apa yang sedang kau lakukan di sini?
The cell phone you used to call her last night was mine, remember?
Kau menelepon dia dari teleponku semalam, bukan?
Because your cell phone needed to be recharged.
Ponselmu mati.
That's why the police called me first.
Itu sebabnya polisi meneleponku lebih dulu.
Because the phone history showed that
Sejarah panggilannya menunjukkan
the conversation took place an hour before it was reported.
kau menelepon satu jam sebelum itu dilaporkan.
What? An hour before?
Apa? Satu jam sebelumnya?
You mean Natsuko didn't fall today?
Natsuko tidak jatuh hari ini?
No. She fell last night a little after nine pm.
Itu terjadi pukul sembilan malam semalam.
No purse or cell phone was found among her belongings
Dia tidak membawa dompet ataupun ponselnya.
so she was unidentified until after noon today.
Kami tak bisa mengidentifikasi dia hingga siang ini.
But, we had a hunch that she could be a teacher,
Tapi kami tahu dia seorang guru.
so we traced her from there
Kami mengikuti petunjuk
and finally found that the victim was Ms. Natsuko Shibuya.
dan mengetahui korban adalah Shibuya Natsuko.
Then her phone was found disposed of inside the park
Kemudian, kami menemukan ponselnya dibuang di dalam taman
so we had you come over.
dan memintamu untuk datang.
And how's Natsuko right now?
Bagaimana keadaan Natsuko?
She's badly hurt with a dented skull.
Tengkoraknya penyok.
She underwent surgery although she's still unconscious.
Dia berhasil melalui operasi, tapi dia masih tidak sadarkan diri.
Is that so?
Begitu...
Natsuko was probably attacked by a mugger on her way home from work
Natsuko mungkin diserang karena uangnya dalam perjalanan pulang kerja
and pushed down the stairs, right?
dan didorong dari tangga.
Yes. We're thinking on that line too.
Ya. Kami sedang menyelidiki kemungkinan itu.
Excuse me...
Hei.
How did you know she may be a school teacher?
Bagaimana kau tahu dia seorang guru?
Because there were a lot of test papers inside the bag
Ada banyak lembar jawaban di dalam tasnya
that was on the ground near her.
itu tergeletak di tanah di dekatnya.
What? Conan, how come you're here?
Tunggu, Conan? Apa yang sedang kau lakukan di sini?
We were taking a drive together.
Kami sedang berkendara bersama.
Were those test papers still untouched
Apakah lembar jawaban itu kosong
with no names or answers on them?
tanpa ada apapun yang tertulis?
Oh, no.
Hah?
The answers were already written in and graded.
Sebenarnya, semuanya sudah diisi dan dinilai.
I think there were papers that scored 100 too.
Kurasa beberapa bahkan mendapat nilai 100 poin.
Then I think that she wasn't attacked here.
Maka, kurasa dia tidak diserang di sini.
Because Ms. Kobayashi said that test papers
Nn. Kobayashi bilang kau seharusnya tidak membawa pulang
that are already graded can't be taken home!
lembar jawaban yang sudah selesai diberi nilai.
She says it's to prevent leakage of private information!
Sekolah tidak ingin informasi pribadi siapapun bocor keluar.
There seems to be teachers who take test papers home to score them,
Beberapa guru memberi nilai ujian di rumah.
but if all the papers were graded,
Tapi jika sudah diberi nilai,
she wouldn't have taken them home, right?
dia tak mungkin melakukan itu.
Which means she was attacked inside the school?
Yang artinya dia diserang di sekolah?
I get it!
Begitu!
In order to make it look as if she was attacked
Untuk membuatnya terlihat seperti dia diserang
on her way back from school,
dalam perjalanan pulangnya,
the perpetrator put whatever was on the desk into her bag
pelaku memasukkan kertas-kertas di mejanya
to make it look that way.
ke dalam tasnya
When doing so,
Saat melakukannya,
the perpetrator without knowing put in the test papers too.
mereka secara tidak sengaja memasukkan lembar jawaban itu.
Since she had a dented skull,
Jika tengkoraknya retak,
she may have been struck with a blunt weapon.
mungkin dia dipukul dengan benda tumpul.
Yes.
Ya.
The perpetrator must have thought that if she was pushed off the stairs,
Mereka pasti berpikir mereka bisa mengelabui kita
the police would overlook the fact that she was struck.
dengan mendorongnya dari tangga.
Come to think of it, Natsuko said on the phone last night,
Dipikir-pikir, Natsuko bilang
"I'm supposed to meet some parents today after this too".
"Aku seharusnya menemui beberapa orang tua setelah ini."
What? Is that true?
Apa? Apa itu benar?
Yes.
Ya.
Okay!
Baik!
Check her call history and e-mails once again thoroughly!
Periksa sejarah panggilan dan surelnya lagi.
The people she had promised to see last night
Siapapun yang berencana untuk menemuinya
are of prime importance!
mungkin penting untuk kasus ini.
Yes, sir!
Ya, tuan!
"Haido Elementary School"
"SD Haido"
Inspector Megure! Here it is!
Inspektur Megure, kami sudah menemukannya!
Luminol reaction from on top the victim's desk.
Ada reaksi luminol pada meja korban.
So the crime took place here after all.
Jadi di sinilah terjadinya.
And, what about the weapon?
Bagaimana dengan senjatanya?
It hasn't been found yet.
Kami belum menemukannya.
The perpetrator probably took it away when fleeing.
Pelaku mungkin membawanya.
Last night,
Semalam,
were there any other teachers beside Ms. Shibuya
apa ada guru lain yang tetap tinggal hingga larut
who remained at school?
kecuali Nn. Shibuya?
No.
Ya.
But Mr. Sugamoto...
Tapi, Sugamoto,
Didn't you say that you were going to take Ms. Shibuya home?
bukankah kau bilang kau memberi Shibuya tumpangan?
Oh, no.
Oh, yah...
"Yoshiharu Sugamoto (30)" -Well, I thought it dangerous for a woman
"Sugamoto Yoshiharu (30)" -Berbahaya bagi seorang wanita
to walk alone at night.
untuk berjalan sendirian di malam hari.
But when I came back here
Tapi ketika aku datang ke kantor fakultas
to see if she'd be ready to go,
karena kupikir dia sudah siap untuk pergi,
she wasn't here.
dia tidak ada di sini.
Around what time was that?
Pukul berapa itu?
I think it was a little after 8:30 pm.
Setelah 8:30, kurasa.
So I asked security to lock up and headed home.
Aku meminta petugas keamanan untuk mengunci dan pulang.
Where and what were you doing till then?
Apa yang sedang kau lakukan sebelum itu?
I was in the PE equipment room organizing the equipment.
Aku sedang menata lemari perlengkapan olahraga.
After all, I'm a PE teacher.
Aku seorang guru olahraga.
Excuse me.
Hei.
Mr. Sugamoto, do you have a car?
Sugamoto, apa kau punya mobil?
Yes. I do.
Ya, aku punya.
But the engine acted up today so I came by train.
Mesinnya bertingkah, jadi aku datang naik kereta hari ini.
What class are you in?
Kau di kelas mana?
You don't look familiar.
Aku tidak mengenalimu.
He's from another school.
Dia dari sekolah lain.
He's here on a social studies field trip, right?
Dia ke sini untuk karyawisata. Benar?
Yep.
Ya.
Inspector Megure!
Inspektur Megure.
Thank you for coming!
Aku sudah membawa mereka.
These two people here are the ones
Ini adalah orang-orang
who had appointments to meet Ms. Shibuya last night!
yang seharusnya bertemu Shibuya.
I thought she was just seeing one parent.
Ada lebih dari satu?
What is going on?
Apa yang sedang terjadi?
Barging in on my company like that?
Polisi menerobos masuk ke dalam kantorku!
I don't know what's going on,
Aku tidak tahu apa yang terjadi,
but please hurry it up
tapi aku harus bersiap untuk makan malam.
because I've got to prepare dinner, okay?
Mari percepat ini.
She was struck by someone last night,
Semalam seorang wanita diserang di sini,
carried over to Haido Park,
dibawa ke Taman Haido
then pushed off the stairs.
dan didorong dari tangga.
Ms. Natsuko Shibuya who had promised to see you both here!
Dia adalah wanita yang seharusnya kau temui semalam, Shibuya Natsuko.
-What? -What?
-Apa? -Apa?
And how is she?
Apa dia baik-baik saja?
Fortunately, the surgery went well,
Untungnya, operasinya berhasil,
but she hasn't regained consciousness yet.
tapi dia masih tidak sadar.
Hey, hold it!
Tunggu!
Don't tell me that we're suspects?
Apa kau mencurigai kami?
You've got to be kidding!
Kau pasti bercanda!
Anyway!
Apapun!
Will both of you please explain what you came to see Ms. Shibuya for?
Bisakah kalian memberitahu kami kenapa kalian menemui Nn. Shibuya?
First, will you please start, Miss?
Kami akan mulai denganmu, nyonya.
I just came to warn Ms. Shibuya not to seduce my son.
Aku hanya datang untuk memberitahunya untuk berhenti menggoda putraku.
Seduce?
Menggoda?
"Akiyo Ueno (39)" -I don't care whether she just came back from the States
"Akiyo Ueno (39)" -Aku tidak peduli jika dia dari Amerika,
but wearing a skirt so short,
roknya itu terlalu pendek.
it's only natural that my son would fall head over heels for her!
Tak heran anak-anak menyukai dia dan pakaian minimnya.
But I think that Natsuko is rather on the plain side.
Tapi busana Natsuko cukup biasa.
He saying that he's going to marry Ms. Shibuya in the future!
Dia bilang dia akan menikahi Shibuya!
I can't just do nothing and watch, can I?
Aku harus melakukan sesuatu!
Your skirt is quite short too, don't you think?
Rokmu juga tampak sedikit pendek.
I'm not a teacher you see.
Aku bukan seorang guru.
You were one before though.
Kau seorang mantan guru.
At around what time did you see Ms. Shibuya?
Pukul berapa kau bertemu Shibuya?
At a little after eight pm.
Setelah pukul delapan.
What did she say back then?
Apa katanya?
She said she'd be careful from now on with a grin on her face.
Dia tersenyum dan bilang dia akan berhati-hati.
I went home in about 10 minutes.
Aku pergi setelah sepuluh menit.
I didn't want to keep my son all by himself for too long.
Aku tak bisa meninggalkan putraku sendirian untuk waktu yang lama.
I came to give that irresponsible teacher a piece of my mind!
Aku datang untuk mengeluh pada guru yang tidak bertanggung jawab itu.
"Fujiyuki Kandachi (41)" -She marked my daughter's answer wrong
"Fujiyuki Kandachi (41)" -Dia menandai salah jawaban putriku
saying that her handwriting was too sloppy.
karena tulisan tangannya buruk!
I came her a little before nine pm,
Aku datang sebelum pukul sembilan,
but the school building was dark
tapi lampu sudah mati
and the gate was closed
dan gerbang sudah ditutup,
so I didn't get to meet her!
jadi aku tidak menemui dia.
Was it really because her handwriting was sloppy?
Apa itu benar karena tulisan tangannya?
Yeah!
Ya.
All the answers that were marked wrong were all correct!
Semua jawaban salahnya sebenarnya benar.
She would've gotten a 100 if graded as should be
Dia seharusnya mendapat 100
but she only got a grade of 60!
tapi dia malah memberinya 60.
I don't think Natsuko would do something unfair like that.
Natsuko takkan melakukan hal yang sangat tidak adil.
Would you like me to show it too you my daughter's test paper then?
Maka, ingin kutunjukkan lembar jawaban putriku?
On top of that, she hired a weird detective too.
Dan dia bahkan mempekerjakan detektif aneh.
A weird detective?
Seorang detektif aneh?
Is that right?
Apa itu benar?
Yeah.
Ya.
I went after her so that I could talk to her
Aku mengikuti dia agar aku bisa bicara padanya di rumah
but I was suddenly grabbed by the collar!
ketika dia menarik kerah bajuku.
It couldn't be helped.
Aku tidak punya pilihan.
She asked me to solve a stalker problem for her.
Dia memintaku untuk menyelidiki penguntitnya.
Bourbon?
Borbon?
I'm sorry I'm late, Inspector.
Maaf aku terlambat, Inspektur.
Did you call him?
Kau menelepon dia?
Well...
Iya...
His phone number was also shown on her call history.
Nomornya ada dalam sejarah panggilannya.
And are those two over there English teachers?
Apa kalian berdua adalah guru Bahasa Inggris atau semacamnya?
No. They are FBI agents
Sebenarnya, mereka adalah agen FBI.
and are cooperating with us with the investigation.
Mereka membantu kami dengan penyelidikan ini.
Oh.
Benarkah?
The FBI?
FBI, ya?
In other words, the Federal Bureau of Investigation of the United States.
Biro Investigasi Federal Amerika Serikat.
I see a lot about you on TV or in the movies.
Aku melihat kalian dalam film dan acara TV setiap saat.
Their investigators show up at crime scenes to steal all the credit,
Penyelidik mereka datang ke tempat kejadian untuk mencuri semua pujian,
smugly interfere with the investigation,
dengan sombong ikut campur dalam penyelidikan,
offend the local police and annoy the viewer.
menyinggung polisi lokal dan membuat kesal penonton.
What?
Apa?
I'm not referring to any of you, though!
Aku tidak bicara tentangmu.
-I just happened to see what I talked of. -This guy...
-Itu hanya cerita yang kebetulan aku lihat. -Anak ini...
This guy tried to kill Akai.
Para pria ini berusaha untuk...
Camel.
Camel.
Cool it.
Tenang.
You don't want him to find out that
Kita tak ingin dia tahu
the FBI knows that he's a member of the Organization, do you?
FBI tahu dia adalah anggota Organisasi.
Okay.
Yah...
What?
Apa?
Then, you're saying that
Kau mengatakan
you're the one who reported the incident involving Ms. Natsuko Shibuya?
kaulah yang melaporkan insiden Shibuya Natsuko?
Yes.
Ya.
She had asked me to investigate on the stalker
Sebagai tambahan menyelidiki penguntitnya,
as well as act as her bodyguard too.
dia memintaku untuk jadi pengawalnya.
I came to watch her as she usually goes home using the park
Aku bermaksud mengawasi dia menggunakan jalan pintas biasanya
which is a short cut.
melalui taman.
But, I didn't think she'd come rolling down the stairs of the park.
Aku tidak mengira dia jatuh dari tangga.
If I remember correctly,
Seingatku,
when you called in to report, you said that somebody pushed her down.
kau bilang seseorang mendorongnya dalam laporanmu.
Did you see the perpetrator?
Apa kau melihat siapa yang melakukannya?
Yes. I saw the perpetrator.
Ya, aku lihat.
The silhouette of the perpetrator who was standing on the stairs,
Siluet pelaku yang berdiri di atas tangga,
looking down at Ms. Shibuya.
melihat ke bawah pada Shibuya.
Unfortunately,
Sayangnya,
I only saw the perpetrator from inside the car
aku melihatnya dari dalam mobilku
and since the perpetrator fled right away
dan dia langsung kabur.
so I couldn't make out the face.
Aku tidak melihat wajahnya.
Only the silhouette.
Hanya siluetnya, ya?
Yes.
Ya.
After that I heard a car take off at the top of the stairs
Kemudian aku mendengar suara mobil dinyalakan dari atas tangga.
so I figured the perpetrator carried her, who was unconscious on the car,
Mereka mungkin meletakkan korban yang tidak sadar di dalam mobil,
took her to the parking lot of the park near the stairs,
membawanya ke tempat parkir di taman dekat tangga,
and after checking to see that no one was around and pushed her off.
mengkonfirmasi tidak ada orang memperhatikan dan mendorongnya dari tangga.
My car was parked on the road but I guess the perpetrator didn't see it
Mereka mungkin tak bisa melihat mobilku di bawah
because it was hidden by the trees.
karena tersembunyi oleh pepohonan.
Haido Park has unrestricted access
Taman Haido punya akses bebas.
but at around nine pm there is virtually no one there.
Hampir tidak ada siapapun di sana setelah pukul sembilan malam.
I believe it was just as Mr. Amuro had explained.
Amuro mungkin benar.
But why didn't you wait at the scene
Tapi kenapa kau tidak menunggu di lokasi
until we arrived after you made the report?
hingga kami tiba?
If you did so, the case would've moved along more smoothly.
Penyelidikannya akan berjalan lebih lancar.
I'm sorry.
Maafkan aku.
I had another client in my car.
Ada klien lain di dalam mobilku.
Since she told me that she didn't want to get involved.
Mereka tidak ingin terlibat.
Are you saying that
Jadi kau mengatakan
you just left Natsuko who was critically injured out on the street?
kau meninggalkan Natsuko terluka di tangga?
Of course I left after confirming that the ambulance arrived.
Tentu saja aku baru pergi setelah ambulan tiba.
Any problem with that?
Apa ada masalah?
Jodie.
Jodie.
Well...
Sekarang...
I guess it's because agent Jodie was best friends with Ms. Shibuya.
Penyelidik Jodie dan Shibuya berteman.
I see.
Begitu.
You're friends.
Dia adalah temanmu?
If so, it could be the doing of someone
Maka itu mungkin perbuatan seseorang
who has a grudge against the FBI.
yang membenci FBI.
You.
Dengar, kau...
Well...
Yang lebih penting...
Why don't we go over the incident once more?
Mari kita coba mewawancarai semua orang lagi.
For now,
Sejauh ini
we know that those three got to or planned to see Ms, Shibuya last night!
mereka bertiga yang bertemu atau berencana untuk bertemu Shibuya semalam.
Right!
Kau benar.
We've got to find the perpetrator first thing.
Kita harus menemukan pelakunya dulu.
The one who struck Natsuko in this teachers' room, knocked her out,
Kita perlu menemukan orang yang membuat Natsuko pingsan disini
carried her to the park and pushed her down!
sebelum membawa dia ke taman dan mendorongnya ke bawah tangga.
Right.
Kau benar.
Then will you tell me about last night without leaving anything out?
Aku juga ingin mendengar setiap rincian kecil yang kau lakukan semalam.
"Next Episode" -So, this is the answer sheet in question.
"Episode Selanjutnya" -Jadi ini adalah lembar jawabannya.
It seems that we were the only ones who could decipher it after all!
Sepertinya hanya kita yang menyadarinya.
-"We"? -"We"?
-"Kita"? -"Kita"?
Right?
Benar?
Conan Edogawa?
Conan Edogawa?
The hospital just called.
Rumah sakit baru saja menelepon!
Ms. Shibuya took a turn for the worse and she's in critical condition.
Kondisi Shibuya memburuk, dan hidupnya dalam bahaya!
Don't die!
Jangan meninggal!
Next Conan, "The Scarlet Pursuit"
Selanjutnya dalam Conan, "Pengejaran Scarlet"